# Florin LIPAN

# About

I'm a Ruby developer with a strong devops background and leadership experience. I've taken various lead roles in the past and like to engage with all sides of product development. I know my way around AWS, Ansible, Kubernetes, Docker and Debian-based systems. I have a personal interest in languages like Crystal and Rust. I've been a full stack developer before and know a thing or two about HTML, CSS and Javascript. I value clean, simple, boring code and try to be pragmatic while keeping my standards high. I can write concise, well structured documentation. I enjoy learning, teaching and being self-organized.

### Personal

Email <u>florinlipan@gmail.com</u>

GitHub / Projects <a href="https://github.com/lipanski">https://github.com/lipanski</a>

Website / Blog <a href="https://lipanski.com">https://lipanski.com</a>
Place of residence Berlin, Germany

Languages Solid English, German, Romanian. Some French.

### Experience

# Jul. 2018 - Present Blacklane / Head of Engineering (Platform)

A partially hands-on management role. I'm providing high-level technical guidance to the Blacklane Platform teams (Infrastructure, Geolocation, Payment, Back-office, Salesforce, Internal APIs), trying to empower developers whenever I can, but getting my hands dirty when I'm needed. I'm handling recruiting and interviews, providing feedback in 1:1 sessions and mentoring team members. I'm trying to keep engineering standards high, apps running smoothly and people engaged and happy.

# Sep. 2014 - Jun. 2018 Blacklane / Lead Backend Developer (Ruby)

A merry mix of backend development, devops, software architecture and management tasks. I helped tame the Rails monolith, designed and partially developed the new Booking API and developed various (micro)services in Sinatra or Rack using MySQL/Postgres, Redis, Unicorn/Puma, Sidekiq/Shoryuken. At some point I got deeper into ops, got familiar with a wide range of AWS services from VPCs to CloudFormation and built our infrastructure around Ansible. Over the course of the last year, we shifted

infrastructure around Ansible. Over the course of the last year, we shifted towards Kubernetes and Docker. I helped define new processes, handled technical interviews and performed product management tasks. I improved the overall performance of our systems and lived to see some beefy infrastructure migration Sundays.

Feb. 2014 - Aug. 2014 Blacklane / Backend Developer (Ruby)

Nov. 2012 - Jan. 2014 Axonic / Full Stack Developer (Ruby on Rails)

A very enriching experience. I developed a fairly complex product (likomi.de) from scratch, being - for most parts - the only developer on the project. Working closely with the CEO, I learned not just full stack development with Ruby on Rails but also what's important to customers, how to talk to

stakeholders and how to plan.

Dec. 2010 - Aug. 2012 Axonic / Full Stack Developer (PHP5, Symfony)

Apr. 2009 - Jul. 2010 Pi Technologies / Developer (PHP, CMS, Javascript)

#### Education

2010 - 2011 Karlsruhe Institute of Technology

M. Sc. Informatics (discontinued)

2006 - 2010 Technical University of Cluj-Napoca

B. Sc. Computer Science (240 ECTS Points) - 9.50/10